Austin Melendez

860-327-3022 • austin@melen.dev • austinmelen.dev

Product Specialist

React Developer and Product Designer with over seven years of professional expertise in building & designing websites, web apps, and working with emerging technologies. Well-versed in HTML5, CSS3 (Sass & LESS), JavaScript (React & Vue), and TypeScript, with a focus on accessibility best practices WCAG 2.1 AA+. Has created engaging and high performing digital experiences for brands ranging from Fortune 500 financial services firms to ivy league higher education organizations, healthcare systems, consumer brands, and non-profits. History of success collaborating with creative, UX, CRM, marketing, accessibility, cybersecurity, and project & account management teams in the delivery of enterprise-level digital experiences.

Core Competencies

• HTML5	Product Design	Illustration	 Accessibility
• CSS3, Sass, Less	• User Experience (UX)	Branding	Visual Storytelling
 JavaScript 	 User Interface (UI) 	 Animation 	 Video Production
 TypeScript 	 Wireframing 	 3D Rendering 	 Photography

Prototyping

Professional Experience

Graphic Design

Nifty's July 2021 to Present

Product Specialist

React

An integral part of launching, maintaining, and improving the Nifty's NFT Marketplace. Using skills fostered throughout my creative career, I'm responsible for assessing user journeys to produce wireframes and optimize user experience throughout the marketplace, producing creative and modern high fidelity page layouts and prototypes, brand & marketing assets, illustrations, and animations to be converted into NFTs. In addition to the product design duties, I'm also responsible for developing HTML components and page layouts using React and TypeScript and styling them using Sass according to approved designs and wireframes. Notable clients include Warner Brothers, Sony, Damien Hirst, Discovery Channel, and more.

Primacy July 2016 to July 2021

Experience Developer

Creative Technologist responsible for collaborating with UX and Creative teams to seamlessly translate build requirements, wireframes, and creative executions into digital experiences. Build page templates in HTML and style templates using CSS (Sass or LESS), add UI functionality using JavaScript, jQuery, or pure CSS. Worked in various tech stacks as specified by clients or internal teams to meet business requirements including but not limited to frameworks such as React or Vue, as well as CMSs including Sitecore, Drupal, Ingeniux, Prismic, and other proprietary systems. Experience integrating websites with Pardot, Salesforce (Marketing Cloud), Google Analytics, HubSpot, and other open source CRMs. Transform and render data from APIs. Perform quality assurance with cross-browser and responsive testing to ensure alignment with creative intent, business requirements and core functionality. Experience developing responsive, accessible email marketing templates and newsletter templates using Pardot. Notable clients included Aetna, The Hartford, Boston College, MIT, University of Kansas Health System, UChicago Medicine, Rice University, Curry College, University of Pittsburgh (launching Q2 2021), Joslin Diabetes Center and more.

Travelers Insurance

Feb 2014 to July 2021

Graphic Designer

Ideate and design logos, brand guidelines, web assets, and social media posts. Lead the creative for the ThinkSafe campaign. Conceptualize and design web layouts for primary Travelers Insurance website. Storyboard, record, and edit videos including performing, recording, and mastering voiceovers, shooting and editing photographs for internal communications, external public relations, and investor relations. Manage and organize stock photography and video filing system.

Turning Hearts Ministries

Sep 2009 to Feb 2014

Designer

Establish brand/identity for the ministry. Ideate and design web assets, social media posts, and print collateral for ministry conferences. Build ministry website/blog on Wordpress. Maintain website and social media accounts. Record, edit, and produce ministry educational videos.

Education

Sport and Medical Sciences Academy – Graduated May 2012

Programs/Tools

• Figma • Github, BitBucket • Prismic • Sketch • Photoshop • Git, SVN After Effects • Zeplin • Illustrator • Jira, Confluence, Linear. Vercel Blender Premiere Firebase Procreate • Unity

Technical Expertise

• Front End Dev • Product Design • Illustration • Animation